Knight, Max; Papers ger050
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Clippings of published stories and essays, 1930-1992; 4; 84 file folders
  - Publications in English, 1945-1992; 4.4
    - "Atomic Birthday Party", Summer 1957 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 49)
    - Knight, M. E. "The Banks of San Francisco", 1948 April (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 49)
    - "The Birthplace of Atomic Energy. A Visit to the Berkeley Cyclotron", 1948 January (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 50)
    - "California", 1949 December (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 50)
    - Knight, M. E. "California Looks Across the Seas", 1946 October 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 50)
    - "California's Third Gold Rush", 1947 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 50)
    - "China Looks Toward America", 1945 April (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 50)
    - "Education Controversy of the Space Age", Spring 1958 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 50)
    - "The Fabulous Galapagos Islands", Spring 1964 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 51)
    - "Farming Without Farms", 1950 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 51)
    - Knight, Max. "The Father of the Comic Strip", 1983 February 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 51)
    - "From the Cradle to the Grave: Greeting Cards!", Winter 1955 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 51)
    - "Grass: Nature's Richest Storehouse", 1952 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 51)
    - "Grotesque World of Christian Morgenstern", Winter 1964 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 52)
    - Knight, Max. "The Happy Adventure of Translating German Humorous Verse", 1992 September (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 52)
    - "How Clean Is That Coffee Cup?", 1951 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 52)
    - "How to be happy in time of crisis", 1952 February (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 53)
    - "Impressions of the Coronation", Summer 1953 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 53)
    - Knight, Max. "The Island Cartoon: A Study in Folklore Psychology", 1990 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 53)
    - "Johann Nestroy, Austria's Philosopher-Clown", Winter 1967 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 53)
    - "Latest Labor Problem -- Moonlighting", Winter 1958 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 53)
    - Fabrizius, Peter and Price Gittinger, Jr. "Let's Face Inbreeding", 1949 October 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 54)
    - "Milk Goes to Alkatraz", 1948 December (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 54)
    - "New Concept in Auto Insurance", 1961 February 18 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 54)
    - Fabry, Joseph and Max Knight. "On the Raising of Ostriches for Little Fun and Less Profit", ca. 1965 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 54)
    - Anonymous. "The Pacific Region of the U.S.A", 1948 July (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 54)
    - "Pursuit of Happiness of the Mundurucu", Winter 1961 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 54)
    - "Return to the Alps", Undated (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 55)
    - "700 pairs of hands make a mural", 1958 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 55)
    - Foster, Peter. "Steel, Wages and Prices. Inflationary Spiral in the United States", 1948 May (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 55)
    - "Stone Age Man Meets Steel Age Man", Winter 1962 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 55)
    - "Talking Without Words", Summer 1957 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 55)
    - "Teaching in a Fishbowl", 1950 July (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 56)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Today's Foreigner -- Tomorrow's Ancestor", Summer 1946 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - "Tourist Glimpses of Yugoslavia", Autumn 1963 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - "Toward a World Government", 1946 July (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - Dehlinger, Klaus. "Two Months on the Mercy Ship 'Hope'. As told to Peter Fabrizius", Autumn 1964 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - Foster, Peter. "Vast Building Programme Admitted Behind Schedule", 1947 January 9 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - "The Vienna Burgtheater", Autumn 1966 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - "Viktor Frankl's Logotherapy", Summer 1964 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - Knight, M.E. "West. Union Maps $60-70 Million Modernization", 1946 November 20 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
    - "You Cannot Live Without Grass", 1951 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 57)
  - Publications in German, 1945-1990; 4.5
    - Twin, Oliver. "Abituriententag 1946", 1946 February (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 58)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Als Grossvater die Grossmutter nahm", 1947 June (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 58)
    - "Amerika stellt sich um. Kriegserfindungen für den Frieden", 1947 September 20 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 58)
    - "Amerikas Blumenkorb", 1949 July 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 58)
    - "An der Geburtsstätte der Vernichtung. Im Hause des kalifornischen Cyclotron", 1947 July 18 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 58)
    - "Der Atomherd der Zukunft", 1959 February 17 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 59)
    - "Auf Amerikas höchstem Gipfel", 1950 February 5 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 59)
    - "Auf Margarinejagd im Nordpazifik", 1954 February 21 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 59)
    - "Bazillenjagd auf Rädern", 1950 June 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 59)
    - "Beethoven ohne Kau-Gummi", 1950 October 6 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 59)
    - "Begegnungen mit drei Menschen", 1949 December 12 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 59)
    - "Bergtouren in der Sierra Nevada", 1948 November 8 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 60)
    - "Beruf: US-Löwenjäger", 1950 July 14 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 60)
    - "Berufschancen in Kalifornien", 1950 March 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 60)
    - "Besuch aus Alaska", 1950 March 31 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 60)
    - "Besuch beim grössten Entdecker aller Zeiten", 1949 November 22 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 60)
    - "Blick ins Mittelalter der amerikanischen Westküste", 1950 February 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 60)
    - "Blitz-Universität am Pazifik", 1950 July 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 61)
    - "Brief aus San Francisco", 1948 January-1948 April (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 61)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Brief nach Wien", 1947 September (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 61)
    - "Carmel -- die Stadt, die es nicht warden wollte", 1951 December 16 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 61)
    - Pf. "Die chinesische Telephonzentrale", 1950 February 2 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 61)
    - "Die Dichterkolonie von San Francisco", 1957 December 13 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 61)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Dieses gewisse Müdigkeitsgefühl", 1946 June (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 62)
    - "Doktorhut in Alaska", 1948 December 27 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 62)
    - "Der Drachenjäger von Wyoming", 1950 May 23 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 62)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Dreimal Toni", 1947 May (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 62)
    - "Durch dick und dünn", 1956 February 3 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 62)
    - "Dürstige Felder. Die Welt braucht Kaliforniens Landwirtschaft", 1948 April 9 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Ein früherer KZ-Häftling bringt Trost nach San Quentin", 1966 August 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Ein wahrer Wildwester: Die Feuerfresserinnen von Cove", 1955 November 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Eine süsse Geschichte. Vom Zuckerrohr Hawaiis zu den Zuckerröhren San Franciscos", 1950 November 16 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Erbeben-Kontrolle", 1953 May 2 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Fahrkarten bereithalten!", 1949 February 17 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Fahrt in die 'letzte grosse Wildnis'", 1949 September 5 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 63)
    - "Die Fledermaushöhle von Arizona. Eine Goldgrube in den Wänden des Grand Canyon", 1958 November 9 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 64)
    - "Die fliegende Fische der Sierra Nevada", 1952 June 13 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 64)
    - "Die Flohfarm von San Franzisko", 1959 March 15 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 64)
    - Foster, Peter. "Fortschritt zum Misthaufen", 1947 July (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 64)
    - Anonymous. "Fred Hickenloopers seltsame Sammlung", 1954 July 29 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 64)
    - "Twin, Oliver. "Freiheit und G'shirrtuch", 1946 April (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 64)
    - "Freundliche Bienen, bitte", 1955 November 2 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 65)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Genesis II", 1947 August (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 65)
    - "Gerettet aus Shanghai. Begegnungen mit den Flüchtlingen in San Francisco", 1949 February 25 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 65)
    - "Die Geschichte eines Verfassungsschöpfers. Zum 75. Geburtstag Hans Kelsens", 1957 February 1 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 65)
    - "Der goldene Nagel", 1948 October 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 65)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Das goldene Wienerherz und The American People", 1946 November (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 65)
    - "Goldsucher", 1948 November 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - "Die grüne Pille. Ungewöhnliche Experimente zur Massenbekämpfung menschlicher Not", 1956 July 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - "Henry Kaiser, der Riese der amerikanischen Westküste", 1948 March 15 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - "Hotels in der Wüste", 1949 March 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Hurra für Bumstead!", 1947 March (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - "Indianerkongress in Neu-Mexiko", 1949 September 15 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - Gosser, Hugh. "Kalifornien erwacht aus dem Eidesrausch", 1958 March 14 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 66)
    - "Kalifornien überwindet die Krise", 1948 October (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 67)
    - "Kaliforniens dritter Rausch", 1958 January 12 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 67)
    - "Kaliforniens Gold", 1947 March 12 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 67)
    - "Kalifornischer Versuchsgarten. Zauberei mit Früchten und Gemüsen", 1959 January 11 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 67)
    - "Kalifornisches Kaleidoskop", 1958 January 3; 1958 August 29 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 67)
    - F., P. "Der Kampf um Stahl im Westen", 1947 May (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 67)
    - "Lebende Gemälde in Kalifornien", 1958 February 9 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 68)
    - "'Lebende Kriegerdenkmäler' in den USA. Schwimmbäder statt Marmorsäulen", 1949 June 30 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 68)
    - "Die Lebenslinie des Westens", 1950 August 25 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 68)
    - "Die letzten Höhlenbewohner Amerikas", 1950 June 1 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 68)
    - "Lichtfahrt", 1948 February 9 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 68)
    - "Der Mann mit dem Hubschrauber", 1956 May 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Die Marquise, F.D.R. und wir", 1946 July (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - "Die Maulesel vom Grand Canyon", 1949 January 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - "Mit dem Briefträger im Wilden Westen", 1950 January 18 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - F., P. "Der neue Präsident der University of California", 1958 November 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - "Neues Leben für den Westen", 1950 July 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - F., P. "Der Nordpol war nie im Pazifik. Theorie der wandernen Pole widerlegt", 1958 December 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 69)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Der Onkel-aus-Amerika Komplex", 1947 April (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 70)
    - "Petroleum unter Wasser", 1949 February 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 70)
    - Foster, Peter. "Der Regenschirm", 1947 February (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 70)
    - "Der reichste See der Welt", 1948 December 23 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 70)
    - "Reklame um jeden Preis", 1948 June 10 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 70)
    - Twin, Oliver. "Sag's mit Clippings", 1946 May (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - Twin, Oliver. "San Francisco bekämpft Discrimination", 1946 August (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "San Francisco gedenkt des grossen Erdbebens", 1956 April 27 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "San Francisco rettet seine Bildfunk-Kultur", 1955 August 5 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "San Franciscos Vorort im Meer", 1950 September 8 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "Schöne Aussichten oder - ? Phantasien der Wissenschaft", 1958 May 18 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "Shakespeare im 'Wilden Westen'", 1950 September 8 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "Die Stadt der Hühner. Blick in den 'Eierkorb der Welt'", 1950 July 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 71)
    - "Die Stadt der vierzehn Hügel", 1949 June 7 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 72)
    - "Trailer-Leben in Kalifornien", 1949 May 5 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 72)
    - "Der Turm des Friedens von Stanford", 1948 October 1 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 72)
    - "Um die Gefängnisreform in Kalifornien", June 1957-1958 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 72)
    - "Unser Leben von Morgen. Vom Rotocycle über den atomischen Kühlschrank zur Marikultur", 1957 June 21 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 72)
    - "Der Unterwasserprofessor", 1958 January 31 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 72)
    - "Der 'verrückte Grieche' hat Recht gehabt", 1958 March 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Versinkt Kalifornien im Meer?", 1957 May 31 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - Gosser, Hugh. "Vogel Strauss-Kongress in San Francisco", 1965 May 6 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Volkszählung auf den Farallonen", 1950 May 4 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Die Wanderschmetterlinge von Pacific Grove", 1958 February 28 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Was mir in Oesterreich auffiel", 1957 August 30 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Weihnachten in New Mexico", 1949 December 25 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Wem gehören die submarinen Schätze?", 1949 August 8 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - "Wenn die Kuh regiert am goldnen Tor", 1950 April 20 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 73)
    - Knight, M. E. "Der Westen und die Welt. Eine Konferenz der 'grass-roots'", 1948 December 17 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - Gosser, Hugh. "Wie radioaktiv sind unsere Nahrungsmittel?", 1958 June 20 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - Kühnel, Max Eugen. "Wiedersehen mit dem Wiener Telephonbuch", 1949 February 25 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - "Wiener, Frankfurter und Hot Dogs", 1958 November 14 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - "Wiener Schnitzelbank mit Kalifornischem Salat", 1956 February 22 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - "Der Wienerschnitzel und das Abstreifmädel. Irrungen und Wirrungen der deutschen Sprache", 1976 April 16 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - "Wissenschaft und Tamtam. Rendezvous der amerikanischen Medizin", 1958 July 13 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - "Zu viel blauer Himmel über Kalifornien", 1949 May 20 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
    - "Zweihundert Millionen Regenwürmer", 1958 October 19 (Box 5 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 74)
  - Translations of articles into Czech, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 1)
  - Translations of articles into Dutch, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 2)
  - Translations of articles into Flemish, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 3)
  - Translations of articles into French, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 4)
  - Translations of articles into Polish, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 5)
  - Translations of articles into Spanish, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 6)
  - Translations of articles into Swedish, Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 7)
  - Friese, Ernst. "Lisa benimm Dich! Musikalisches Lustspiel in fünf Bildern", Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 8)
    Typescript of drama.
  - Friese, Ernst und Rudolf Weis. "Lisa, benimm dich! Musikalisches Lustspiel in einem Vorspiel und drei Akten". Playscript, copyright 1939 (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 9)
  - Fricker, Peter Racine. "Some Superior Nonsense". Score. Text by Christian Morgenstern, translated by Max Knight", Undated (Box 6 (4-Clippings of published stories and essays), Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous materials, 5; 6 file folders
  - One and One Make Three, Undated (Box 6 (5-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 11)
  - Fabry, Joseph. Publications by, 1949-1995 (Box 6 (5-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 12)
  - Fabry, Joseph, Undated (Box 6 (5-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 13)
    Clippings about.
  - Miscellaneous clippings and notes, Undated (Box 6 (5-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 14)
  - Poetry, miscellaneous materials, Undated (Box 6 (5-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 15)
  - Tikvah -- Network of Holocaust Survivors in the Bay Area, Undated (Box 6 (5-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 16)